# Sam Brown

## **SKILLS**

**Languages** PHP, JavaScript

Frameworks Laravel, Magento, WordPress, React Native

Frontend Livewire, React, Vue.js, jQuery, Tailwind,

Bootstrap

**Databases** MySQL, Redis

DevOps & Server Admin AWS, Digital Ocean, Linux, Bash, Docker, Vagrant

Tooling

Git, Gulp, XDebug, PHPUnit, Pest

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Consultancy - Full-Stack Developer

March 2023 - PRESENT

- Advised Stephenson Law on critical infrastructure requirements for Roost.
- Developed the Migo platform and other web-based tools for Rubric Law.
- Worked on a social network (with integrated scoring system) for a leading US sporting goods company.
- Built the second generation of the Irish Sailing Club membership platform.

#### **Stephenson Law** — Lead Developer

October 2021 - March 2023

- Formed a new in-house development team and established the team's best practices.
- Took ownership of existing custom applications and developed new ones.
- Built a business-critical customer portal and record compliance system, integrating with various back-office applications and external APIs.

### Worktribe - Full-Stack Developer

March 2020 - October 2021

- Worked closely with designers and product owners to build a new cross-platform React Native application covering desktop, browser and mobile, driven by a headless Laravel API and websockets server.
- Worked on bug fixes and support for the existing legacy PHP application.

#### New Vision Software - Software Developer

October 2017 - March 2020

- Refactored a legacy, procedural PHP application for a leading energy broker. Applied clean code practices and design patterns to produce maintainable, scalable and object-oriented code.
- Built multiple API middleware services for clients, to synchronise data between systems in real-time.

## **EDUCATION**

## **University of South Wales, Newport** - Degree

2010 - 2011

Documentary Film & Television (BA Hons)

## **About**

I have significant experience building production software, API integrations and working across the stack. I focus on making exceptional products and have a skill for developing great UX. I have a level-headed and pragmatic approach to problem-solving with excellent attention to detail and quality. Great communication skills, able to convey ideas clearly.